export const SOCIALSTUDIESA2005 = [

{
id: "question1",
question: "1. The practice whereby people marry within the clan is referred to as",
A: "exogamy.",
B: "endogamy.",
C: "polygyny.",
D: "polyandry.",
answer: "B. endogamy",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question2",
question: "2. The performance of full marriage rites in the traditional society is very important because it",
A: "enhances the status of the children in the family.",
B: "gives the children the opportunity to be educated.",
C: "gives opportunity to the children to acquire wealth",
D: "enhances the status of the family.",
answer: "A. enhances the status of the children in the family",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question3",
question: "3. Marriage under the ordinance requires all the following except that the",
A: "banns are published for à period of twenty-one days.",
B: "couple should come from the same country.",
C: "man must not be legally married to any woman.",
D: "woman must be more than eighteen years old.",
answer: "B. couple should come from the same country",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question4",
question: "4. The fundamental rights of couples to decide on the number of children they want to have and their spacing are referred to as",
A: "birth rights",
B: "family rights.",
C: "natural rights.",
D: "reproductive rights",
answer: "D. reproductive rights",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question5",
question: "5. The nuclear family is a primary group because",
A: "members have affection for each other.",
B: "it is the smallest unit in any society.",
C: "it is the first unit that the child interacts with.",
D: "all the children are taken good care of.",
answer: "C. it is the first unit that the child interacts with",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question6",
question: "6. Which of the following statements is not true of the Interstate Succession Law in Ghana?",
A: "It is used to share part of a deceased’s property not covered by the will.",
B: "It is used to share the property of a deceased who died without leaving a will.",
C: "It has been introduced to replace the will.",
D: "Surviving spouse, children and members of the extended family have a share in the property of the deceased.",
answer: "C. It has been introduced to replace the will",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question7",
question: "7. The inheritance process under the nuclear family system is simple because property is",
A: "passed on to the eldest son",
B: "given to the children of the deceased.",
C: "passed on to family head",
D: "taken care of by the law courts.",
answer: "B. given to the children of the deceased",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question8",
question: "8. The spread of sexually transmitted diseases (STDs) can be limited through",
A: "conducting frequent STD tests.",
B: "having regular vaccination.",
C: "isolating STD patients.",
D: "discouraging promiscuity",
answer: "D. discouraging promiscuity",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question9",
question: "9. One of the major reasons for the high rate of population growth in traditional societies is that in such societies",
A: "infant mortality rate is high.",
B: "the men are generally well-to-do;",
C: "a woman’s prestige is determined by the number of her children.",
D: "the fertility of women is very high.",
answer: "C. a woman's prestige is determined by the number of her children",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question10",
question: "10. Physiological needs of an individual consist of",
A: "food, shelter, clothing and water",
B: "love, affection, togetherness and acceptance.",
C: "security and protection from physical harm",
D: "respect, honour and praises",
answer: "A. food, shelter, clothing and water",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question11",
question: "11. Self-identity refers to",
A: "the sum total of a person’s education and training.",
B: "the sum total of a person’s wealth and position in society.",
C: "the sum total of a person’s perception and beliefs.",
D: "one’s name and the tribe one belongs to.",
answer: "C. the sum total of a person's perception and beliefs",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question12",
question: "12. If one wants to develop oneself; one must begin with",
A: "identifying one’s potential.",
B: "getting support from family members.",
C: "acquiring formal education.",
D: "establishing one’s own personality trails.",
answer: "A. identifying one's potential",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question13",
question: "13. What a person is, at any moment is called",
A: "other self",
B: "real other",
C: "real self",
D: "ideal other",
answer: "C. real self",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question16",
question: "16. The status of a person in a traditional society depends on one’s",
A: "own achievements",
B: "ethnic affiliation",
C: "religious beliefs",
D: "physical structure",
answer: "A. own achievements",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question17",
question: "17. The most important aim of formal education to the society is",
A: "acquiring higher academic excellence",
B: "acquiring vocational skills",
C: "helping the individual secure a well-paid job in the community",
D: "making the individual fit well into the community",
answer: "D. making the individual fit well into the community",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question18",
question: "18. Which of the following ensures peaceful co-existence in the society?",
A: "Sacrificing personal desires for the collective good of society",
B: "Insisting on individual rights",
C: "Ensuring that laws made by leaders are obeyed",
D: "Everyone contributing equally to the progress of society",
answer: "A. Sacrificing personal desires for the collective good of society",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question19",
question: "19. Which of the following social problems is Ghana likely to experience if the population continues to grow rapidly?",
A: "Negative ethnic sentiment",
B: "General poverty",
C: "Religious conflicts",
D: "Discrimination against women",
answer: "B. General poverty",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question14",
question: "14. Which of the following account for the high productivity in the private sector?  \nI.	Effective supervision \nII.	Provision of incentives \nIII.	Institution of long service award \nIV.	Strong labour union",
A: "I and II only",
B: "I, II and III only",
C: "III and IV only",
D: "I, III and IV only",
answer: "A. I and II only",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question15",
question: "15. The efficiency of a country’s labour force is determined by",
A: "availability of jobs",
B: "level of education",
C: "higher wages",
D: "welfare services",
answer: "B. level of education",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question20",
question: "20. Most often the youth are not actively involved in decision-making in the society because they are",
A: "impatient and arrogant",
B: "not knowledgeable",
C: "inexperienced in life",
D: "immature to work",
answer: "C. inexperienced in life",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question21",
question: "21. The poor conditions in Ghana’s prisons tend to",
A: "harden inmates",
B: "reform inmates",
C: "minimize crime",
D: "eradicate crime",
answer: "A. harden inmates",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question22",
question: "22. One of the major functions of the Electoral Commission is",
A: "appointing members of parliament",
B: "nominating cabinet ministers",
C: "making arrangement for the conduct of elections",
D: "selecting political parties’ representatives",
answer: "C. making arrangement for the conduct of elections",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question23",
question: "23. The most important benefit of traditional festivals is",
A: "enabling members of the community to make merry",
B: "bringing citizens together to plan the development of their area.",
C: "generating income for individuals",
D: "providing opportunities for the people to meet their loved ones",
answer: "B. bringing citizens together to plan the development of their area",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question24",
question: "24. In traditional society, people who lead exemplary lives, are after they are dead, referred to as",
A: "Heroes",
B: "Martyrs",
C: "gods",
D: "Ancestors",
answer: "D. Ancestors",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question26",
question: "26. The golden lion at the centre of the Coat of Arms of Ghana represents the country’s link with the",
A: "Commonwealth",
B: "United Nations",
C: "African Union",
D: "Non-Aligned Movement",
answer: "A. Commonwealth",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question25",
question: "25. Which of the following are means of controlling moral degeneration among the youth?  \nI.	Providing guidance and counselling  \nII.	Promoting religious education  \nIII.	Promoting tertiary education  \nIV.	Organizing cultural festivals",
A: "I and II only",
B: "I and III only",
C: "II and IV only",
D: "III and IV only",
answer: "A. I and II only",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question27",
question: "27. Ghanaians can contribute their quota to nation-building through all the following ways except",
A: "payment of taxes",
B: "obedience to the law",
C: "commitment to work",
D: "adherence to religious rites",
answer: "C. commitment to work",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question28",
question: "28. According to the constitution of Ghana, any group of individuals who make an attempt to overthrow a constitutional government can be charged with",
A: "Misdemeanour",
B: "Murder",
C: "Felony",
D: "Treason",
answer: "D. Treason",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question31",
question: "31. What leaders require from their followers in order to achieve success is to",
A: "singing their praises",
B: "avoid criticizing them",
C: "be loyal and cooperative",
D: "Have formal education",
answer: "C. be loyal and cooperative",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question29",
question: "29. National integration can best be achieved through",
A: "religion and customs",
B: "tolerance and understanding",
C: "sports and language",
D: "education and skills training",
answer: "B. tolerance and understanding",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question32",
question: "32. Which of the following leadership styles allows followers to fully participate in decision making?",
A: "Democratic",
B: "Authoritarian",
C: "Paternalistic",
D: "Laissez-faire",
answer: "A. Democratic",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question33",
question: "33. Social harmony under multi-party democracy depends on",
A: "Faithfulness",
B: "Honesty",
C: "humility",
D: "Tolerance",
answer: "D. Tolerance",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question34",
question: "34. The doctrine which ensures that no two arms of government are entrusted to the same person or group of persons is known as",
A: "rule of law",
B: "checks and balances",
C: "separation of powers",
D: "constitutional rule",
answer: "C. separation of powers",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question30",
question: "30. The practice of separation of powers as well as checks and balances under constitutional rule is meant to",
A: "prevent the opposition from winning elections",
B: "prevent arbitrary and tyrannical rule",
C: "control freedom of speech and movement",
D: "give absolute power to the president",
answer: "B. prevent arbitrary and tyrannical rule",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question35",
question: "35. One of the factors which prevents the realization of the rule of law is",
A: "a high rate of illiteracy",
B: "low incomes for workers",
C: "entrenchment of regimes",
D: "a high rate of unemployment",
answer: "C. entrenchment of regimes",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question36",
question: "36. A major problem facing the Economic Community of West African States (ECOWAS) is the",
A: "poor weather condition in the sub-region",
B: "lack of an African high command",
C: "Poor attendance at summit meetings",
D: "Non-payment of dues by members",
answer: "D. Non-payment of dues by members",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question37",
question: "37. The basic aim of international trade is to",
A: "generate funds for local government",
B: "exchange goods for other goods",
C: "get resources to build more schools",
D: "enable many people to be employed",
answer: "B. exchange goods for other goods",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question38",
question: "38. Protecting the environment can best be done through",
A: "drying industrial waste",
B: "redirecting river channels",
C: "practicing traditional farming",
D: "re-cycling waste",
answer: "D. re-cycling waste",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question39",
question: "39. A natural cause of desertification is",
A: "annual bush burning",
B: "dry weather condition",
C: "Over-cultivation",
D: "Over-grazing",
answer: "D. Over-grazing",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question40",
question: "40. The term environment refers to",
A: "the cultural and social surroundings of human beings",
B: "the occurrence and interaction of animals",
C: "living organisms and their surrounding",
D: "the immediate social and physical surroundings",
answer: "D. the immediate social and physical surroundings",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question42",
question: "42. The natural resources of Ghana have not been not been sufficiently exploited mainly because of",
A: "limited market for the products",
B: "inadequate finance",
C: "low technical know-how",
D: "insufficient foreign investment",
answer: "C. low technical know-how",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question43",
question: "43. Which of the following most adversely affects the development of Ghana?",
A: "Underdeveloped natural resources",
B: "High brain drain",
C: "Low interest rates",
D: "Trade liberalization policy",
answer: "B. High brain drain",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question44",
question: "44. Which of the following is responsible for the low standard of living in Ghana?",
A: "Autocratic leadership",
B: "High dependency ratio",
C: "High mortality rate",
D: "Inadequate basic education",
answer: "B. High dependency ratio",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question41",
question: "41. A good member of a community is the one who",
A: "keeps the laws and customs of the community.",
B: "is gainfully employed in the country.",
C: "learns the customs and laws of the community.",
D: "knows all the customs and laws of the community.",
answer: "A. keeps the laws and customs of the community",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question45",
question: "45. The principle of self-reliance implies",
A: "consuming what is produced locally",
B: "producing more than is needed",
C: "Producing what you need",
D: "using only local raw materials for production",
answer: "A. consuming what is produced locally",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question46",
question: "46. A major advantage of irrigation is that it ensures",
A: "quick maturing of plants",
B: "bumper harvest",
C: "soil enrichment",
D: "all-year round farming",
answer: "D. all-year round farming",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question47",
question: "47. All the following are functions of the entrepreneur except",
A: "managing the enterprise",
B: "providing capital for investment",
C: "promoting trade union activity",
D: "seeing to the welfare of workers",
answer: "C. promoting trade union activity",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question48",
question: "48. The destruction of the vegetation cover contributes to",
A: "global warming",
B: "acid rain formation",
C: "depletion of mineral deposits",
D: "decrease in the ultra-violet rays",
answer: "A. global warming",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question49",
question: "49. In a country where democracy is practiced,",
A: "the president has absolute power",
B: "decisions are quickly taken",
C: "members of parliament are appointed",
D: "fundamental human rights are protected",
answer: "D. fundamental human rights are protected",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question50",
question: "50. The values and customs passed on to people from their ancestors are referred to as",
A: "folklore",
B: "heritage",
C: "lineage",
D: "Taboo",
answer: "B. heritage",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},


]